<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: VPS | Old Guy, New Trick]]></title>
  <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/categories/vps/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-17T09:56:09-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://hogihung.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ho Gi Hung]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enable Remote Access - Postgres]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2015/01/07/enable-remote-access-postgres/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-07T21:00:07-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2015/01/07/enable-remote-access-postgres</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently I&rsquo;ve been troubleshooting an issue with my pet project.  On my laptop, in a development environment, I didn&rsquo;t seem to have any issues. My test suite has been working fine, but when I deployed the app to a production environment, I started to discover some issues.  Issues that revolve around the database.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not a SQL guru, so from time-to-time when I want to poke around my Postgres database, I use an application called PGAdmin.  So I fired up PGAdmin and tried to connect to the Postgres database that is running on my server, over the internet.  Politely, PGAdmin told me to go pound sand &ndash; it was not able to connect.  After a little research I learned that there were two files on my server, related to postgres, that I needed to update.</p>

<p>On your remote server, that has Postgres running, modify the two files indicated below:<br>
<em>(Note: your path might be different depending on your version of Postgres and your Linux distro)</em></p>

<pre>
sudo vim /etc/postgresql/9.3/main/pg_hba.conf  
# Added by jfhogarty to support remote access and PGAdmin
host    all             all             0.0.0.0/0               md5


sudo vim /etc/postgresql/9.3/main/postgresql.conf 
#The next line added by jfhogarty to enable remote access and PGAdmin
listen_addresses = '*'

</pre>


<p>Lastly, with the above changes added to the two .conf files, we need to restart Posgtres:</p>

<p><code>
sudo service postgresql restart
</code></p>

<p>With the above changes in place, and postgres restarted, I fired up PGAdmin again on my laptop.  And like <em>butter</em> I was able to connect to and work with my databases. I resumed debugging my original issue.</p>

<p><em>Learn Something New Every Day</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom Passwordless SSH Access]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/custom-passwordless-ssh/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-06T20:10:14-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2015/01/06/custom-passwordless-ssh</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I created my Digital Ocean VPS I setup SSH Keys for both my main laptop and desktop computers.  I grabbed the appropriate contents from my .pub file and pasted that information on the web form for &lsquo;Add SSH Key&rsquo; under the SSH Keys menu of my droplet.  However, I noticed that each time I would ssh to my server I would be required to input my password.</p>

<p>In this blog posting I will illustrate how I solved this issue and why the word &lsquo;custom&rsquo; appears in the title.  There are many websites that cover how to setup passwordless ssh login.  For example, Digital Ocean has a nice posting: <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/how-to-set-up-ssh-keys--2">here</a></p>

<p>However, those instructions, and other like it, assume a plain-vanilla setup.  Of course, I dare to be different.  For example, before I started to solve this puzzle, my ~/.ssh directory had the following:</p>

<p><code>
➜  .ssh  ls -la
total 88
drwx------  11 jfhogarty  staff   374 Jan  6 18:36 .
drwxr-xr-x+ 93 jfhogarty  staff  3162 Jan  6 20:10 ..
-rw-r--r--@  1 jfhogarty  staff  6148 Mar  9  2013 .DS_Store
-rw-------   1 jfhogarty  staff  1766 Mar  2  2013 id_rsa
-rw-r--r--   1 jfhogarty  staff   400 Mar  2  2013 id_rsa.pub
-rw-------   1 jfhogarty  staff   668 Apr 20  2014 jh-mbp_id
-rw-r--r--   1 jfhogarty  staff   614 Apr 20  2014 jh-mbp_id.pub
-rw-r--r--   1 jfhogarty  staff  7162 Jan  5 21:17 known_hosts
➜  .ssh
</code></p>

<p>The id_rsa (private file) and the id_rsa.pub (public file,) are your normal files one would find.  But I&rsquo;ve implemented a &lsquo;best-practice&rsquo; adopted from my day job and I create specific key files for different types of access.  For example, following the instructions in the link above, from the Digital Ocean article, I created the following:</p>

<p><code>
-rw-------   1 jfhogarty  staff   668 Jan  5 21:11 do_id_dsa
-rw-r--r--   1 jfhogarty  staff   614 Jan  5 21:11 do_id_dsa.pub
</code></p>

<p>If you follow the steps from the link, there is one thing that you may need to do in addition to their steps.  Some systems require that you change the file permissions for the authorized_keys file located on your target computer.  For example, the following is how I have the permissions set on my VPS:</p>

<p><code>
➜  .ssh  ls -la
total 12
drwx------  2 jfhogarty jfhogarty 4096 Jan  5 21:16 .
drwxr-xr-x 11 jfhogarty jfhogarty 4096 Jan  6 20:14 ..
-rw-------  1 jfhogarty jfhogarty  614 Jan  5 21:14 authorized_keys
➜  .ssh
</code></p>

<p>I adjusted the permissions using the following syntax:</p>

<p><code>
chmod 600 authorized_keys
</code></p>

<p>After creating the new keys on my laptop, and updating the authorized_keys file on the remote server, I thought surely I should now be able to login without using a password.  I was wrong!  The remote server continued to prompt me for my password.  I decided to call it a night as it was getting late.</p>

<p>While working on a VM issue today for my day job, my internal lightbulb went off and I realized what the problem was.  Lets take a fresh look at the .ssh directory of my laptop:</p>

<p><code>
sh  ls -la
total 88
drwx------  11 jfhogarty  staff   374 Jan  6 18:36 .
drwxr-xr-x+ 93 jfhogarty  staff  3162 Jan  6 20:21 ..
-rw-r--r--@  1 jfhogarty  staff  6148 Mar  9  2013 .DS_Store
-rw-------   1 jfhogarty  staff   668 Jan  5 21:11 do_id_dsa
-rw-r--r--   1 jfhogarty  staff   614 Jan  5 21:11 do_id_dsa.pub
-rw-------   1 jfhogarty  staff  1766 Mar  2  2013 id_rsa
-rw-r--r--   1 jfhogarty  staff   400 Mar  2  2013 id_rsa.pub
-rw-------   1 jfhogarty  staff   668 Apr 20  2014 jh-mbp_id
-rw-r--r--   1 jfhogarty  staff   614 Apr 20  2014 jh-mbp_id.pub
-rw-r--r--   1 jfhogarty  staff  7162 Jan  5 21:17 known_hosts
➜  .ssh
</code></p>

<p>The keen eye might notice that I now have three sets of private/public keys.  However, when I was typing ssh myhostname.com ssh didn&rsquo;t know which files to use, if any.  I was able to prove my theory by trying the following:</p>

<p><code>
ssh -p 9986 -i ~/.ssh/do_id_dsa myhostname.com
</code></p>

<p>And BAM!  No password required to login.  I was on to a solution.  When I had my lightbulb moment, I had remembered that I needed to create a config file in the .ssh directory on my laptop.  Lets take a look at it:</p>

<p>```
➜  .ssh  cat config
Host 10.11.12.13
IdentityFile ~/.ssh/do_id_dsa
Protocol 2</p>

<p>Host myhostname.com
IdentityFile ~/.ssh/do_id_dsa
Protocol 2</p>

<p>➜  .ssh
```</p>

<p>NOTE:  To protect the innocent, the IP Address and *.com name above are fake.  Please substitute those values for your real IP Address and/or domain name.</p>

<p>And that is how I solved my customized passwordless ssh access to my VPS.</p>

<p><em>Learn Something New Every Day</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
