<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ruby | Old Guy, New Trick]]></title>
  <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/categories/ruby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-15T18:03:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://hogihung.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ho Gi Hung]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Week At Bloc]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/03/15/first-week-at-bloc/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-15T19:46:34-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/03/15/first-week-at-bloc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>About two weeks ago I was trying to decide which on-line web developer education solution I would enroll in.  The decision was not easy.  Along with the weekly time requirements, roughly 25 hours per week, the financial cost is nothing to shrug off.  In the end I choose Bloc (<a href="http://www.bloc.io">http://www.bloc.io</a>)</p>

<p>My training at Bloc started this past Monday, March 10th.  The Bloc course runs about 12 weeks, broken down into four segments:</p>

<pre><code>1.  Environment Setup / Programming with Ruby
2.  Rails Foundation
3.  Features/Testing/Javascript
4.  Project Challenges
</code></pre>

<p>I&rsquo;ve just finished item 1 &ndash; Environment Setup / Programming with Ruby.  When I read the description of this section my first thought was, &ldquo;this should be easy.&rdquo;  I have been exploring Ruby and Rails for almost a year.  I&rsquo;ve installed RVM on several computers, worked with GitHub and Heroku, as well as several introductory tutorials.</p>

<p>And many of sub-sections in this first track were a nice and quick completion for me.  But, through each sub-section, I did learn something new.  For example, while working on setting up an app on Heroku, I learned how to add support for New Relic.  I&rsquo;ve seen ads and mention of New Relic a lot while learning Rails but never took a look at it.  Now I&rsquo;ve had a nice gentle introduction.</p>

<p>There are 20 sub-section to Environment Setup / Programming with Ruby.  I felt good and confident as I traversed through them one by one.  I was slowed down briefly in sub-section 14 &ndash; Arrays.  One of the exercises there introduced me to new code and techniques I had not yet experienced.  I love learning new stuff!</p>

<p>As I rounded out this section, I found myself staring at my nemesis &ndash; Blocks.  I don&rsquo;t know why, but I seem to have a mental <em>block</em> when it comes to Blocks (as well as Procs and Lambdas.)  This section took me a bit and I had to reach out for help.</p>

<p>In the Bloc program, each student has a mentor.  We have around 3 calls a week with our mentors.  When I got stuck it was after I had last talked with my mentor.  Not a problem &ndash; Bloc also has a staffed on-line chat room.  I popped in to the chat room and asked a question.  One of the staff there gave me a nudge.  After about 30 minutes I was still stuck.  I had gotten further, but still hadn&rsquo;t solved the problem.  Another question/discussion in the chat room and it became clear.  I was able to complete the lesson.  <strong>Happy Dance!</strong></p>

<p>I look forward to my next call with my mentor (tomorrow) and starting my next section &ndash; Rails Foundation.  As I progress through each section I&rsquo;ll return here to provide updates.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby, RVM, Cmd Line SheBang!]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/02/12/command_line_apps_rvm/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-12T10:56:35-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/02/12/command_line_apps_rvm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I ran across this tip while reading the book <em>&ldquo;Build Awesome Command-Line Applications
in Ruby 2,&rdquo;</em> by David Bryant Copeland.  Although most of the code I&rsquo;ve been practicing
has been Ruby on Rails, at my day job we utilize a lot of command line applications.  I&rsquo;m on a mission to add Ruby to our toolbox which currently is Perl and shell scripts.</p>

<p>For a recent project I needed a command line application that could take a CSV
file as an input, extract out some data, and create a new pipe (|) delimted text
file.  I use RVM on my personal laptop and desktop, so I installed it on our
company server.  At that time, Ruby was at version 1.93.  Not too long after, I
added 2.0.0 and 2.1.0.  But my application was written in 1.93.  It is a simple
application so the version shouldn&rsquo;t matter.  But in case it does, you may find
value in this tip.</p>

<p>If you are a RVM user, and type the command &lsquo;which ruby&rsquo; at the command line, you
may get something similar to:</p>

<p><code>
/Users/jfhogarty/.rvm/rubies/ruby-2.1.0/bin/ruby
</code></p>

<p>You can use that as the first line of your ruby script:
```</p>

<h1>!/Users/jfhogarty/.rvm/rubies/ruby-2.1.0/bin/ruby</h1>

<p>```</p>

<p>However, if you want your script to use whatever the current version of Ruby is,
or if Ruby is in a different location on a machine other than yours, you can use this syntax:</p>

<p>```</p>

<h1>!/usr/bin/env ruby</h1>

<p>```</p>

<p>This tip is found on page 4, in the section: &ldquo;Shebang: How the Systems Knows an App Is A Ruby Script&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
