<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ruby | Old Guy, New Trick]]></title>
  <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/categories/ruby/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-24T12:56:54-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://hogihung.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ho Gi Hung]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wrap Up - Bloc Experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/07/24/wrap-up-bloc/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-24T12:05:14-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/07/24/wrap-up-bloc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been bad.  I let myself get consumed by my attendance of the on-line course at Bloc, and spending a lot of after-work-hours working on my personal project.  I have neglected my writing, and I apologize for my absence.</p>

<p>Earlier today I received notification from Disquis that someone, Nalani, had submitted a comment.  I am grateful for that comment as it reminded me of absence from this blog.  So with that nice kick-in-the-pants, let&rsquo;s move forward.</p>

<p>I completed my on-line training of the Bloc.io course on June 9th 2014.  Overall I was satisfied with the training and can confidently recommend it to others, depending on their situation.  What?</p>

<p>Bloc is not for everyone.  The first barrier to overcome is the cost.  I believe I got in before the price increase so the tuition was around $4250 if memory serves me correctly.  I believe the price to be fair for what you get.  However, I would not suggest that anyone plop down that money if they are currently struggling financially.</p>

<p>Depending on your employment needs, Bloc may not be for you.  For me, I took the course to better my programming skills and to assist me move forward with my personal project.  But I would not say that what I learned would allow me to get a job similar to what I have now, at my current pay rate.  I think the education would help one land a junior-developer job or an internship at a dev shop.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not an expert, but from my experience with local dev shops here, there is a heavy emphasis on testing and Test-Drive-Development(TDD.)  And when I took the Bloc course, that area was lacking.  You can see my previous post for more information.</p>

<p>Yesterday I received an email from Bloc that indicated that they improving the Full Stack program by adding more testing to the course.  Not sure if it was my feedback, or feedback from many of us past students, but I&rsquo;m glad to see that they continuously improve on their product.</p>

<p>Is Bloc for you?  Maybe.  If you are like me, someone who has a day job and wanted to improve their programming skills, while trying to bring your product idea to life, then yes.  Maybe you are someone with a great idea, a founder, and want to get a better grip on what it will take to produce your product.  I think Bloc can help you there.  If you are trying to break ground in the industry and land your first job or internship, then yes, I think Bloc is for you.  If you need the extra hand holding while learning the basics, then yes I think you will get value from the Bloc program.</p>

<p>I do want to end with a note about the mentorship, and you may have read into my words at the end of the last paragraph.  If you are seeking what I consider advance knowledge and/or assistance, you may be dissapointed.  While I found the mentorship to be very helpful at the beginning and middle of my training, I was dissapointed at the end when it came to my capstone project.  Fortunately for me, about 8 weeks in to my Bloc training, I met a guy, Shaun, who became my &lsquo;external-mentor.&rsquo;  If not for him, I would not have been able to complete some of the Bloc assignments the way I wanted &ndash; via TDD.  Sure I could have completed them, but I want to develop by writing tests first.  Shaun has also helped me with my personal project and taken it so much farther than I could have done on my own.  What I&rsquo;m trying to end with is this &ndash; no matter if you take the training at Bloc or else where, find a mentor who will spend the time with you to help you learn.</p>

<p><em>Learn Something New Every Day</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enter the 4th Block]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/05/11/enter-the-4th-block/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-11T18:05:24-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/05/11/enter-the-4th-block</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Picking up from where I left off with my block experience (see previous post, Week 2 and a half at Bloc,) a lot of good things, and some bad things, have occurred.  I had finished, what was called at the time, the third block, which included lessons on RSpec, Testing Users and both creating and destroying using Ajax.</p>

<p>The end of Block Three took me a bit longer to complete compared to how I progressed through the first two blocks.  The material in the third block was new to me.  It was during the end of this block, and creeping into the beginning of block four that I began to have issues with my mentor.  In the first two blocks, since I didn&rsquo;t need much help, I didn&rsquo;t mind that our sessions tended to be brief.  Usually they ran up to 10 minutes.  But our sessions are booked for 30 minutes.</p>

<p>My mentor during this time had missed a some meetings and had asked me to reschedule a few times.  I&rsquo;m flexible so I didn&rsquo;t see an issue.  But there was one time that I needed to reschedule and the mentor wouldn&rsquo;t work with me to make up the time.  Time much needed as I was having trouble with the project I had selected in Block Four &ndash; Saas Wiki Collaboration Tool.  I was getting very frustrated.</p>

<p>I reached out to student coordinator at Bloc, Karen, and discussed the issues I was having.  I explained that in the beggining I had gotten ahead, but now with all the problems I was encountering with this mentor, I was getting behind.  And I felt it very disrepectful that I was asked on several occasions to modify my schedule for him, but the one time I needed a re-schedule, he didn&rsquo;t care.</p>

<p>Karen helped me out and let me pick out a new mentor.  She said that they would add a week to my enrollment to help make up for some of the lost time.  (Think I need to check on that because it doesn&rsquo;t look like they added a week.)  The new mentor, Charlie, was a huge improvment.  Never did I feel like he was trying to get me off the phone.  In fact, on several calls we went over the scheduled 30 minutes.</p>

<p>While working with the new mentor, Charlie, has been a much better experience, I feel that there is something missing from the program.  Although it is said that students will do pair programming and testing, I don&rsquo;t find either to come near what I was expecting.  It may be that my expectations are set to high from what the folks at Bloc had planned to offer.  I can understand that they have a range of differently skilled students.  I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;m far off in saying that most newbies to this program probably don&rsquo;t care as much about testing as I do.</p>

<p>I find this mediocre approach to testing to transcend into the help one would get in the Office Hours Chat room.  I&rsquo;ll provide a brief example.  I was stuck on how to write a test that would make sure that any user, other than a logged in user, would not be able to access the ability to upgrade a users account by direct url navigation.  When I posed my question the answer I got was that I should use Pundit&rsquo;s policies and don&rsquo;t display the upgrade button unless the user is logged in and allowed to upgrade.</p>

<p>I had explained that I had already written tests for that, and the code to make the tests green, but I wanted to ensure that a malicous user would not be able to access the url for an upgrade directly.  The short answer I got was &ldquo;&hellip;well the users shouldn&rsquo;t do that.&rdquo;  Yeah, well credit card thieves should not steal peoples credit card info and identies either, but I&rsquo;m sure the credit card companies do whatever they can to protect against those thieves.</p>

<p>I really don&rsquo;t think the program was meant to take testing as seriously as I am.  It seems the program gives one just enough to say, &ldquo;&hellip; yeah I know how to test with RSpec.&rdquo;  Although I&rsquo;m happy with my mentor Charlie, I felt a bit frustrated on our calls when trying to work through testing issues.  So frustrated in fact that I stopped testing the proper way and just worked on trying to complete the assignment.</p>

<p>Bloc changed the student dashboard and I got really worried.  I was reviewing where I was in the program and the dashboard was telling me that I was behind.  The dashboard lists 5 projects, including the one I was working on, Saas Wiki Collaboration.  The sixth project is for our capstone.  Seeing that I had only four weeks left, and still hadn&rsquo;t finished this Wiki project, I got a bit frazzled.  It is not like I haven&rsquo;t been putting in the time!</p>

<p>On my mentoring call with Charlie last Friday I asked what the deal was.  There was no way I could finish all those projects and have time for my capstone.  My previous mentor had said that I only needed to pick one if I wanted to spend more time on the capstone project.  Luckily, Charlie confirmed that the dashboard was a bit confusing.  Students have the option to do more than one project before their capstone, but it is not required.</p>

<p>That made me feel a bit better, but I still needed to wrap up this Wiki project.  The main reason I took this course was to work on my capstone and have help when/where I needed via the mentorship and Office Hours Chat room.  Please don&rsquo;t get me wrong, I have learned a lot via the program, but my main goal is to work on my personal project.</p>

<p>With some &lsquo;external&rsquo; help, I was able to wrap up this Wiki project.  At least I believe it to be done according to the original requirements.  I even was able to get the Stripe intergration to work, with tests!  I&rsquo;ll have another blog post regarding the external help &ndash; stay tuned!</p>

<p>I have another mentoring call on Monday &ndash; 05/12/14.  We should be able to discuss my capstone project and get an idea of how to get started.  The nice thing about the Saas Wiki project is that there are a lot of components of that app which will apply to my capstone project.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more information regarding my experience at <a href="http://www.bloc.io">Bloc.io</a>  I will be publishing an overview of the program at the conclusion of enrollment.</p>

<p><em>Learn Something New Every Day</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[3 Noobs at Lillys]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/04/17/3-noobs-at-lillys/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-17T22:10:08-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/04/17/3-noobs-at-lillys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This evening I attended the RubyJax OpenHacks event at Lilly&rsquo;s Cafe out at the beach.  I believe the normal schedule has the OpenHacks event on the third Thursday of each month.  I like to get to th event a bit early as parking in that area can be a royal pain.</p>

<p>Shortly after I settled in, another new guy to the group, Jesse, joined me.  I had met Jesse a previous week at one of the Code &amp; Coffee events.  We got to talk a little bit about ourselves and what we were trying to accomplish in our quest of learning.</p>

<p>Enter the third n00b, Josh.  I was starting wonder if Micah has set the three of us in a fun game of snipe hunting.  Get all the new people together and laugh at them from a distance.  :)  The three of chatter a bit back and forth for a while, sharing some of our experiences.</p>

<p>One can learn from others that are new to Ruby, or anything for that matter.  For example, Jesse share a neat tool he was using with me called Dash (<a href="http://kapeli.com/dash">http://kapeli.com/dash</a>).  This is a neat little app that sources the documentation of too many to count languages and frameworks.  I downloaded the app while he was demonstrating, and was excited to see all of the reference material available for the subjects I was interested in.  And then some!</p>

<p>I shared my current experience with Bloc.io and demonstrated their website, including a sample of some of the lessons I had completed and the one I had just started &ndash; my big project.  About this time Michah had showed up and I know that at least I felt at ease.  Micah had helped me before with some learning and I was hoping to pick his brain again.</p>

<p>Before we get to that though, Josh took a turn at sharing some resources.  The one that really stuck out to me was this website:  <a href="http://gitimmersion.com/">http://gitimmersion.com/</a>  I found this site to be a great resource, for the beginner, in learning how to use git.  So far I&rsquo;ve made it up to lab 14.  What I find really useful about this site is that I will be able to use the lessons on the site to help educate my fellow team workers at my day job.  Trying hard to get us all to use version control.</p>

<p>Just at I was getting ready to ask Micah a question, we had another join our group.  I was surprised, but very please to see Paolo Perrota join our group.  I think it is safe to say that all of use new guys were very happy to be hanging with two Ruby Gurus.</p>

<p>Rounding out the evening I reached out for some help with a coding issue I was having.  For the OOB Web app that I&rsquo;ve been developing for the day job, I need to support an older app.  This app uses the same data that I&rsquo;m migrating to the web app.  But the data in the files that support the app need to be delimited with a : and contain fields that we no longer need.  I had been able to figure out how to build that information as a : delimited export via the browser, but what I really needed was a rake task that could build two text files.</p>

<p>Working with Micah, he showed me where I was doing things correctly, and where I was making some mis-steps.  Using his guidance I was able to finish writing my second rake job &ndash; exporting the data.  I don&rsquo;t recall if I have mentioned it before, but Micah also helped me construct my first rake job &ndash; importing the data.</p>

<p>The time at Lilly&rsquo;s flew by, but I&rsquo;m confident in saying that all of us newbies learned something useful.  Looking forward to the next Code &amp; Coffee and OpenHacks events.</p>

<p><em>Learn Something New Every Day</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ancient City Ruby 2014 Day Two]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/04/07/ancient-city-ruby-2014-day-two/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-07T18:35:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/04/07/ancient-city-ruby-2014-day-two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Day two was a rough start for me.  I over slept a little bit so I didn&rsquo;t have time to get breakfast at home.  Luckily, there was some breakfast provided at the conference.  I&rsquo;m not a big carb eater, but I knew that if I didn&rsquo;t eat something, it would be a rough day.  So down went a half bagel, some fruit, a glass of water and a coffee chaser.</p>

<p>Starting out the day was someone I had heard of, but never met &ndash; Terence Lee.  Terence works at Heroku as well as participates on the Ruby core team as a contributor.  I enjoyed this talk because I&rsquo;ve been using Heroku in my knowledge quest and found the topic to be relevant.  I think we sometimes take for granted what is going on behind the scenes, by guys like Terence, to ensure easy deployment of our apps.  In summary &ndash; make sure you are off of Ruby 1.8.7 and 1.9.2.</p>

<p>For day two, I took the most notes during the second talk by Craig Kerstiens.  He talked about Postgres which is the primary database that I&rsquo;ve been using in my Rails applications.  Craig confirmed something that I had encountered two days earlier &ndash; don&rsquo;t use homebrew for Postgres.  Download and use the Postgres.app from their website.  I had a lot of issues during my workshop due to homebrew and its installation of Postgres.  Along with good tips for Postgres related resources, I also learned new stuff like sequential scan vs index scan.  And using Gin for indexing when you have multiple values in a column vs the standard BTree index method.  Rounding out his talk, I walked away with a to-do list of required research on HStore and jsonb.</p>

<p>Lunch on day two was the only part of the conference I didn&rsquo;t like.  I am not a pasta fan at all and sadly didn&rsquo;t find much I could eat.  I ended up snacking on two pieces of cheese and a chunk of bread.  Where the meal failed for me, the desert was a home run!  So I filled up on desert and coffee.  Yup, I was a bit jittery for the rest of the day.</p>

<p>After lunch it was time for Aaron.  His presentation had both a healthy serving of comedic relief as well as filling geekery.  Who else but Aaron would code a way, using a webcam, to scan all of his Magic the Gathering cards and catalog their value?  Oh and did I mention there were cats?  Aaron urged the audience to help him test out one of his projects related to OpenCV.  We were to all send him a tweet with the words &ldquo;Photo Me&rdquo;.  The goal was for his program to see the tweet, take a picture of Aaron at that moment in time, and send the picture to the person who tweeted him.  Well it seems one variable wasn&rsquo;t accounted for &ndash; Twitter.  With a flood of incoming requests to his Twitter account, the &ldquo;enforcers&rdquo; locked his account.</p>

<p>Something that I had forgotten to mention earlier was that for most of the conference, Ben sat with me.  I really thought this was cool.  Most of the speakers sat together up front or to the side.  But I got to sit with Ben &ndash; just me and him.</p>

<p>Which brings me to one of Ben&rsquo;s friends &ndash; Konstantin.  Ben had made some reference to Konstantin in his presentation &ndash; well more like to Konstantin&rsquo;s bag which apparently got lost while enroute to a conference in the Philippines.  Konstantin had a good bit of humor in his presentation which focused on security.  It was very englightening to learn about the many different ways hackers try to compromise web applications, including Rails applications.  Both the Ruby and Rails teams make a great effort to eliminate/prevent security issues.  I&rsquo;ll admit there were parts of the talk that went over my head.  But overall, I found it very usefull and an area where I want to learn more.</p>

<p>Near the end of Konstantin&rsquo;s talk I started to feel the effect of not eating a proper lunch, and an overload of sweets.  I started getting a little light-headed.  So the end of the conference was a bit of a blur.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve only been to two Ruby related conferences &ndash; Ruby Conf 2013 in Miami, and now this one, Ancient City Ruby Conf 2014.  Although the one if Miami was much larger, I enjoyed the Ancient City one more.  I felt like I learned more at ACR and fit in better.  At the conference in Miami I very much felt like an outsider.  But at ACR I met a lot of people from all over the US and the world.  I am looking forward to another Ancient City Ruby conference in 2015!</p>

<p><em>Learn Something New Every Day</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ancient City Ruby 2014 Day One]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/04/06/ancient-city-ruby-2014-day-one/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-06T20:55:09-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/04/06/ancient-city-ruby-2014-day-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The actual conference was split across two days, and followed the single-track format.  This was unlike my experience at Ruby Conf 2013 &ndash; Miami, which was multiple topics going on concurrently.  For the first day, the following speakers were lined up:  Leon Gersing, Justin Searls, David Copeland, Katrina Owen, Richard Schneeman, and Ben Lovell.  Of all those speakers, I only had ever heard of three, and as it so happened, met each one of them: Justin Searls, Katrina Owen and Ben Lovell.</p>

<p>In a quick summary of the day, I wrote the most notes from the talk by Leon, learned the most from Katrina&rsquo;s talk and laughed my ass off, and learned some stuff, from Ben&rsquo;s talk.  Justin talk also had my interest and I had jotted down some notes from his presentation.</p>

<p>I really liked Leon&rsquo;s talk as to me it was not directly programming/developer related, but more so a spiritual and inspirational discussion.  I don&rsquo;t know if it was planned this way, but I believe it was perfectly executed as the first talk of the day &ndash; really set a good mood and environment.  Something that Leon said really moved me.  He said: &ldquo;Twitter, Facebook, Instagram are all simulations of relationships.&rdquo;  I thought that was very powerful.</p>

<p>Before I continue, I just want to say that I enjoyed all of the talks from the speakers on this day.  But given my current skill level with Ruby and as a programmer, some of the talks were more moving and relevant to me.  I&rsquo;m sure others had similar, but different results.</p>

<p>Three speakers in, some brief talks by some sponsors as well as lightening talks, and it was time for lunch.  I really enjoyed the lunch that was provided at the hotel for the conference.  Not only was the meal yummy, but the deserts were great as well.</p>

<p>On a nice full stomach, with a big smile on my face, it was time for Katrina&rsquo;s talk.  I really enjoy her presentation style and I feel that the delivery was at a level that I was able to absorb.  Katrina took us through a refactoring session for &ldquo;Bob.&rdquo;  Frightenly, some of that code looked familiar :)  If you get a chance, you can check out her prentation at: <a href="https://speakerdeck.com/kytrinyx/overkill">Overkill</a></p>

<p>Being the last speaker on a given day is a tough task.  People tend to start getting tired.  Leave it to Ben to fire up the crowd.  He had all of us rolling with laughter from his opening remarks to his closing arguments.  And along the way we learned a bit about testing APIs.  Watch out for those &ldquo;f#$@ing sharks!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Day one didn&rsquo;t actually end after Ben&rsquo;s talk.  That evening some of the conference attendees went on the Ghost Ride, while the rest of us got to do the Pirate Ship adventure.  Even though I live in Jacksonville, which isn&rsquo;t too far from St. Augustine, I had not ever been on the Pirate Ship.  It was a lot of fun.  I just wish that I had my heavier hoodie and it got a bit cold on the water.  On the ship I got to meet a few other people from Hash Rocket, including Paul Elliott.  I had heard Paul&rsquo;s voice on several episodes of the Ruby5 podcast, and it was nice to meet him in person.</p>

<p>All-in-all, day one was a big hit for me.  Oh, I almost forgot!  At the beginning of the day, before the first talk started, I got to meet and shake hands with Aaron Patterson.  Yeah, you could say I&rsquo;m a fanboi of his.</p>

<p><em>Learn Something New Every Day</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
