<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blog | Old Guy, New Trick]]></title>
  <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/categories/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-05T22:13:38-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://hogihung.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ho Gi Hung]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bad CS vs Good CS]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/03/04/bad-cs-vs-good-cs/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-04T21:16:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/03/04/bad-cs-vs-good-cs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Why is bad customer service still an issue in the present day?  I realize we had to put up with it in the past whether it was due to lack of competition, or a lack of a way to widely communicate our experience.  But in the age of the Internet, and lightspeed communications, what the hell?</p>

<p>I know this isn&rsquo;t about programming, but every once in a while I will chat about general topics.  This past week I got to experience both bad and good customer service.  I was shocked actually becuase the bad service was from American Express.  I&rsquo;ve never had an issue with them until this past week.  I&rsquo;ve been an American Express member for over 20 years.  Last year and the year before I used my card for purchases in excess, well let&rsquo;s just say greater than $20k each year.  I make my payments online via the American Express website.  This past time I made an error.  I didn&rsquo;t catch that I used my business account instead of my personal account.  When Amex went to transfer the money, there wasn&rsquo;t enough in the business account.  They emailed me a the next day.  A day after that I got a letter from my credit union letting me know that Amex tried to transfer money and since I didn&rsquo;t have enough, they hit me with a fee.</p>

<p>So I called Amex.  First person said, &ldquo;&hellip;sorry, nothing I can do.  We will keep trying to hit that account up to three times.&rdquo;  Oh and they will charge me a fee each time it fails.  And, my bank will charge me a fee each time it fails.  Now I realize I made a mistake.  But seriously, Amex couldn&rsquo;t cancel the transaction?  I escalated to a supervisor and got the same response.  I told the supervisor that I wanted to file a formal complaint.  Their response &ndash; &ldquo;&hellip;noted, but there is nothing we can do.&rdquo;  ARGH!</p>

<p>So I called my credit union (bank) to see if I would have better luck.  They were a little confused at first because they thought I didn&rsquo;t want to pay.  I did want to pay, but I needed to use the right account and I didn&rsquo;t want to keep getting dinged by both sides.  The Vystar rep helped me out and provided a solution.  1.)  File a stop payment to block the Amex transaction.  2.) Helped me transfer the money Amex was trying to get from my personal account to business account.  The reason being was in case the block didn&rsquo;t take affect quick enough, there would be money for Amex to get and no more penalty fees.  In addition, the Vystar rep reversed the charges/fees that occurred from their end.  Now that is Customer Service!</p>

<p>But wait, there is more!  After providing a solution, the rep said &ldquo;&hellip;you know we have a promo now for our bank card.  Would you like to get one?&rdquo;  And I did.  All future transactions where I used to use my Amex will now be done with my Vystar Card.</p>

<p>What I find worse than bad customer service, is customer service that just ignores you.  Before I began my journey with Ruby and Rails, I was trying to build upon my knowledge of PHP.  I purchased a book, <em>&ldquo;Easy PHP Websites with The Zend Framework,&rdquo;</em> by W. Jason Gilmore.  I found this book not very good &ndash; a little better than the phpCake one I had tried, but not worthy of the money I had spent.  I reached out on several occasions to get a refund.  I was ignored.  Contrast that horrible experience to a good one that happened this week.  I had heard about the book <em>Geocoding on Rails</em> by the folks at Thoughtbot.  I was very excited because from what I had heard, this book might help with a hurdle I had been trying to leap in my own app.  I got the book and tried to follow.  Had some trouble.  Tried again a few other times when I thought I was more alert.  Still didn&rsquo;t help.  Then I came to realize that I had made a mistake &ndash; I thought the book would take the reader from start to finish of a Geolocation Rails app.  But the book is geared more so to explain the different concepts and ways to approach Geolocation in a Rails app.  In other words &ndash; it was above my level, above my pay grade.</p>

<p>I reached out to Thoughtbot and asked for a refund.  Not only did they promptly refund my money, but they encouraged me to revisit once I get a bit further along in my Ruby studies.  I&rsquo;m sure the book, and some others they offer, will be of better value to me once I gain more knowledge.</p>

<p>Customer Service need not be hard.  I&rsquo;m not saying the customer is always right.  But the customer pays the bills.  In the case of Amex, I would have been ok if all they had said was: &ldquo;&hellip;no problem, I&rsquo;ll stop that transaction for you.&rdquo;  Reversing the penalty would have been a bonus, but I&rsquo;d be ok with them just stopping the offending transaction.</p>

<p>Amex, you&rsquo;ve lost a long time customer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drop the Bass (Fat)]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/02/26/drop-the-bass/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-26T10:39:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/02/26/drop-the-bass</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I ran into a former co-worker the other day &ndash; someone that I hadn&rsquo;t seen since I left my previous assignment back in 2008.  They looked at me in a surprising way and at first I wasn&rsquo;t sure why.  Had I changed that much in a few short years?  Then it hit me,
the last time I saw this person, I was 60 pounds heavier!</p>

<p>Back in 2008 I had probably hit the height of feeling like crap.  The job I was in was stressing me out and then we found out that our contract was not going to be renewed.  Although the job was not making me happy, the thought of being unemployed was worse.  Tack on to that, I kept gaining weight over the years and I was having health problems.</p>

<p>I kept getting sick and having a hard time breathing.  I was coughing all the time, and though I deny it, the wife says my snoring could rattle the dishes.  I saw several doctors, and specialists.  They ran tests on me, put me in some type of chamber to measure how I breathed.  Nothing was fixing my problem.  The only relief came from cough syrup, assorted pills and some breathing medication.</p>

<p>In 2009 I started a new job, one that I&rsquo;m still at and very happy with.  The stress from the old job was gone, but the fat was still sticking around.  We had a family trip planned to go to Hong Kong in December.  Hong Kong is a very dynamic city and I wouldn&rsquo;t have my crutch of a car/truck to shuttle my fat ass around with.  I&rsquo;d have to walk and use the mass transit.</p>

<p>In August of 2009 I finally admitted to myself, partly because I saw that I couldn&rsquo;t keep up with my kids and partly because I saw a picture of myself, that I really needed to loose weight.  I did some research and came across a program called &ldquo;Quick Weight Loss&rdquo; which can be found at: <a href="http://quickweightloss.net">http://quickweightloss.net</a>  They had locations in some cities where you could go for consultation and get advice on what plan(s) to use.  But I wasn&rsquo;t located in any of those cities.  Luckily, they had an at-home program.  I signed up and started the plan in September 2009.</p>

<p>By the time we left for Hong Kong, in mid-December, I had lost 50 pounds and was feeling great!  I only gained 2 pounds while on vacation in Hong Kong, though I ate whatever I wanted.  One gets plenty of excercise getting around that city.  When I returned to the states, I went back on my program and lost another 10 pounds for a total loss of 60 pounds.</p>

<p>Fast forward to 2013.  I have gained a little of the weight back.  We had a family cruise this past December, and I ate a lot of great food.  I&rsquo;ve lost some of that weight on my own.  Occasionlly I&rsquo;ll jumpstart my weight correction by going back on the QWL plan.  Thankfully though, it is usually just for 2 weeks so I can loose that naughty weight and get back to my desired numbers.</p>

<p>Did I mention all those health problems I was having are now gone?  Not only did a loose those pesky pounds, I also lost all of the health problems I was having.  And although I still say that I don&rsquo;t snore, my wife says that it is much &ldquo;lighter&rdquo; than it was.</p>

<p>Working in the tech field may seem to present challenges in staying fit.  We basically sit all day to earn a living.  But I&rsquo;m encouraging you to watch your weight and loose those pesky pounds.  While at work, stand up every 30-45 minutes and stretch out.  Stay standing for 5-10 minutes and get then get back to work.  Maybe get one of those desks that can go up and down &ndash; I have my eye on this one: <a href="http://www.nextdesks.com/terra">http://www.nextdesks.com/terra</a></p>

<p>So, get up and Drop that Bass, er, Fat!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost Free Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/02/19/almost_free_blog/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-19T20:55:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/02/19/almost_free_blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Would you like to have your own super cool blog but don&rsquo;t want to go through the hassel of setting up WordPress?  Or maybe you don&rsquo;t have your own hosting service like DreamHost but still want a blog.  Are you bummed out since Apple killed off iWeb?</p>

<p>Well the good news is there is a nice solution for us programmers.  And it can be free if you don&rsquo;t want a custom domain name.  For this site, the only cost was purchasing the domain name &ndash; oldguynewtrick.com.  I&rsquo;m a fan of Hover for domain registration (<a href="http://hover.com">http://hover.com</a>) This site is powered by the Open Source application called Octopress (<a href="http://octopress.org">http://octopress.org</a>) and hosted, for FREE, on GitHub.</p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t have a GitHub account, and you are a programmer, what the heck are you waiting for?  You can get a free GitHub account, hop on over to <a href="http://github.com">http://github.com</a>  (There are paid versions as well.)</p>

<p>In a future posting I will go over the steps that I performed in order to setup an Octopress powered site on GitHub.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code & Coffee (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/02/18/Coffee_And_Code/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-18T19:10:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/02/18/Coffee_And_Code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My journey to learn Ruby and Rails started almost one year ago.  I&rsquo;m embarrased to admit, aside from a couple of lunch meetings, I&rsquo;ve been traveling down this road on my own.  Being new to the language and community, plus the fact that I&rsquo;m an introvert, I found it hard to get out and meet fellow programmers.</p>

<p>Near the end of last year I decided to try and conquer my fear and looking back on it, I probably should have started with a smaller introduction to the Ruby community.  In November of last year I attended Ruby Conf 2013 in Miami, Florida.  Don&rsquo;t get me wrong, I enjoyed almost everything about my experience there.  But I felt so out of place.  I went by myself and had no clue on what to expect.</p>

<p>After my experience with Ruby Conf, I decided that I need to take a more gentle approach to entering the fabulous programming community.  I looked up RubyJax since I live in Jacksonville, FL.  I saw that they host many events &ndash; most at the Hash Rocket office at Jax Beach.</p>

<p>So I&rsquo;ve signed up for as many meet ups as I could, which include <em>&ldquo;Code and Coffee.&rdquo;</em>  This was hard for me on a couple of levels.  First, I still feel inadequate as new member of the Ruby community.  Second, I work from home and am really not a morning person.  To get up at 6:15am so I have time to shower and drive to Jax Beach is a bit tough.  It was especially tough for me today, my second Code &amp; Coffee, because I was not feeling 100%.  I enjoyed going last week but in my mind it was clear I was the new guy and I felt really dumb as I was surrounded by so many great programmers.</p>

<p>Then something happened.  At this second Code &amp; Coffee, I wasn&rsquo;t the new guy anymore.  A new member showed up, I believe his name was Michael, and I was able to talk with him and give some advice based on my experience as a new person to the Ruby community.  I hadn&rsquo;t realized how far I have come in my journey.  Don&rsquo;t get me wrong, I still have far to go, but when that light bulb went off in my head, it really brightened my day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
