<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: General | Old Guy, New Trick]]></title>
  <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/categories/general/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-24T21:54:25-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://hogihung.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ho Gi Hung]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/02/08/introduction/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-08T20:01:25-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://hogihung.github.io/blog/2014/02/08/introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to my blog.  I&rsquo;m just an old guy that is trying to learn new tricks every day.  Well, I&rsquo;m an old guy in the sense that my daughter came up to me one day and asked if I had used quills to write with when I was in school.  Though I did use a quill in art class it wasn&rsquo;t because that is all we had &ndash; it was just to illustrate how the tool worked.</p>

<p>There is a saying along the lines of <em>&ldquo;You can&rsquo;t teach an old dog new tricks.&rdquo;</em>  I don&rsquo;t really believe this and I thought I&rsquo;d twist the words a bit and use it as a catchy domain name, thus &ndash; OldGuyNewTrick.com</p>

<p>I don&rsquo;t consider myself old as a mid-forties guy, but for keeping with the fun, I&rsquo;ll play the role of an old guy and the context of a &lsquo;trick&rsquo; is me learning how to code in Ruby and Rails.  Well actually web development in general, but the focus is on Ruby and Rails.</p>

<p>I will leverage this blog to document my journey and share my experiences.  Years ago I had toyed with blogs and tools like WordPress.  I really hadn&rsquo;t given any thought to starting a new blog until I heard several well known people in the Ruby community, for example Ben Orenstein, suggest that if one is a programmer, they should have a blog.</p>

<p>Will anyone ever read this?  Why have a blog?  At first I disagreed with them and wasn&rsquo;t going to do it.  But it was like the universe was talking to me.  The topic of having a blog kept coming up in conversations, podcasts, and screencasts.  And I had a thought &ndash; even if no one reads this but me, it will still be useful.  By writing down my experiences I will have a good reference to look back on.  I may figure out a solution to a problem this week, and have a similar one a year from now.  But being an old guy, I may not remember, so I can refer back to this blog.</p>

<p>I am not well known in the programming community, but I plan on making a dent in the community.  On twitter and github I go by hogihung.  I wouldn&rsquo;t get all giddy and jump over to GitHub to see what I&rsquo;ve done &ndash; you&rsquo;ll be disappointed.  Remeber, I&rsquo;m new at this.  All I have is learning demos up there at the moment.</p>

<p>Ho Gi Hung is my Chinese name and I tend to use it as my internet persona.  My given name is John F. Hogarty, glad to meet you.</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"><img src="/images/avatar_jh.jpg" width="80" alt="My Avatar" /></p>

<p>One last item to note &ndash; this blog is created using Octopress and hosted on GitHub.  I&rsquo;m still learning how all this works, so please bear with me as I work out the kinks.  :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
